[Music]
A lot of changes are taking place in this module.
Earlier, there was a lot of investment business
and one had to work hard for insurance.
Now, the insurance business has become
very easy and the investment
business has become very difficult. That is why
many people who did not pay attention to insurance earlier are
now doing insurance
business, especially health
insurance business. In such a situation,
when you are doing health insurance business,
you will have to pay attention to many things. To
give information about those things,
Mr. Amay Vaidya is coming now. Amay Vaidya is a professional
financial advisor from Mumbai. He does his
financial advisory work
and he has a very good grasp on the subject of insurance.
So let's meet Mr.
Amay Vaidya. Hello friends, I am Amay Vaidya and I
welcome you all through this BE TV. Friends, it has been a
few days, a few weeks. In fact,
we are observing that because the
business of LIC and mutual funds has become a little
slack, so many
insurance advisors are
now diverting towards health insurance.
Business is also doing very well,
but friends, this is a platform to
educate and make you all aware
and for good sharing. So,
I would definitely like to share one point with you
friends, such that for so many years,
whose core business has been life insurance or
mutual funds, the product
explanation is very easy because it is
mainly dealing with the savings
returns based on certain amount
of death cover. Basically, whatever
terms and conditions there are are very minimal, but
in health insurance, if you
look at the terms and conditions and waiting periods, they are
quite high. Along with that, there is
a
huge
laboratory for the permanent exclusions. If anyone fails to tell this thing, then at the time
of claim, there can be a
huge clash between the customer and the advisor.
So, as responsible advisors, it is
our duty to
first study the terms and conditions of the policy ourselves
and make the customer aware of this. Friends,
this is nothing special, but during the season of Covid
In this time of the ongoing Covid pandemic, it is
very important to talk about it
and I will tell you the reason for this,
friends, in all the bills we have seen before Covid, there are
many such expenses
which are being incurred today but were not incurred earlier,
such as hygiene cost, staff management
cost, PPE
cost, after that service charges, these were
not usually levied, friends, you will agree with me
that the expenses paid in the medi claim policy are
mainly
for the treatment of the patient and at that time
we pay room rent, nursing fees,
ICU charges, blood oxygen,
ventilator, medicine, nursing anesthesia, OT
charges, surgeon
fees, if you have bought any implants like knee
implants for knee replacement,
cataract surgery, lenses, all this
money goes to us because it can be directly
linked to the treatment of the customer or the patient,
but what we were seeing before this,
friends, everything was covered in the room rent,
meaning
whatever hygiene or cleaning is there of the room, it will
naturally be taken from the room rent.
Whatever the staff expenses are, they will be
taken from the room rent or nursing cost. But today we are seeing that
room expenses have increased a lot.
But
apart from this, there are staff management charges, service
charges, then
your night admission charges, emergency
admission charges, Sunday admission charges,
hygiene and sanitation charges, then
your medical disposables. So,
usually these expenses used to be
taken from the room rent. But today what we are seeing is that
separate bills are being charged in all cases
and almost all the
insurance companies do not cover these expenses.
Friends, when we explain the medical policy
to a customer, he
goes to the hospital with the mindset that I have cashless
facility. I will show the card and
whatever the bill comes, I will get the full amount.
So, after admission, if we
go into firefighting mode and say that sir, you will
not get this, you will not get that, I
told you, you do not remember, then there is
a dispute between the customer and the
agent, so it is a duty of the customer.  Each and every
advisor should inform them as soon as possible, be it
through a video or through a customer meet
or through a message,
that Sir or Madam, in
whatever mediclaim policy you have taken, you are going to get these
things,
we are not going to get all these things. What happens is that the customer will not get these things
because we will inform them in advance
or if we inform them, then
they feel that my advisor is a little
knowledgeable, he wants to educate me and is
telling me what is legal, what
is not legal, what is allowed and not allowed.
After getting admitted in the hospital, he or
his relatives remain in panic mode, no matter
how much you try to explain to them,
they will not be able to understand. It is a request
to you that kindly educate the customer on all the
charges. Secondly, many of you will be
associated with many companies to
sell mediclaim policies and the most
crucial point in it is room
rent. Friends, room rent, this category has
many aspects, some companies have
limits, some  There is no limit in companies,
so if there is a
room rent
limit in whichever company you are associated, then you should know one more thing that if he gets
admitted in a higher room category, then whatever
package cost there is,
doctor's fee, surgeon's fee, OT charges, all these,
as the room rent increases, the
entire cost will increase accordingly and
in such a situation, if his eligibility for room rent is
less and he has gone to a higher category
room, then
he will not have to pay only the difference amount of the room, he may have to pay the entire
package cost which is of the difference amount,
so it is a request to you that
kindly first educate yourself and then
educate your customer
so that in case of claim there won't be any
dispute friends and one more thing I would
like to tell you that if anyone has a
mediclaim policy in two insurance companies,
then request him to go for cashless in the
company in which the higher sum is insured.
Apply because
if you have policies of two medical companies while getting admitted in the hospital, then
you get cashless cover from only one
company because only one
set of original papers is made, so
after settlement, if any balance amount is
left, then you have to take its photocopy and
submit it to the other company, otherwise
this thing will not be covered in
cashless cover. So as advisor it is our
duty to request the customer that if
possible, do not keep your policy in two different insurance companies, take only
one policy,
take a big policy because when we take medi claim,
it is mainly taken for cashless cover. No
one carries 20, 25, 50 lakhs in his pocket.
If the case becomes critical and
progresses towards organ transplant,
in that situation, if the expense goes up to 30, 40 lakhs,
your base policy is of 5 lakhs, on that
you get cashless cover. But there
is a top up policy of 25 lakhs taken from another company,
you will not get cashless cover in that, so
what is the benefit of taking such a mediclaim policy?  It
is requested that you
inform the customer that
if you have policies from two different insurance companies, then
if a big claim comes in one go, then
you will get cashless cover from only one insurance
company because almost all the
hospitals will make you cashless cover from only one company
because it is
natural that only one set of original papers is made
which they have to submit to that company
Friends, I hope that whatever
initiative we are taking, it is a
selfless approach of educating you so that
you succeed in
insurance business with this I
wish you all the best and if you have any
doubts with regards to health insurance,
please feel free to get in touch with us
Thanks a lot So if you are a financial
advisor then you must have understood that
after Covid, there have been many changes in health insurance claims.
Despite having a health insurance policy, the customer will have to
bear many extra expenses from his pocket.
If the customer gets this information in advance then there will be
no problem at the time of claim, otherwise the client  You will be
more worried at the time of claim and you should vent your
frustration on your financial advisor
and secondly if the base plan is small
and the top up policy is big and there are chances of a big claim then
for cashless you should choose the top up policy
because cashless will be possible only with one policy
Amay ji thank you very much for giving such important information about health insurance services and
claims
friends BA TV we have created this channel
especially for lakhs of financial
advisors of India if you
want to come and talk on the platform of BA TV then do
contact us thank you very much for watching and listening to BA TV
if you have not subscribed to this channel till now then
subscribe to it
click on the bell icon for notification
and if you like the video then like it too
[Music]